Matt Finucane / CV 1 of 2

Dublin, Ireland // me@mattfinucane.com // https://mattfinucane.com

Profile

I have over eighteen years of postgraduate experience working with a wide variety of projects across multiple domains and in different workplace settings, both on-site and remote.

I focus on building web and mobile applications that are performant, scalable, and easy to maintain. I adhere to industry standards of the highest quality and work with Open-source software.

Skills

- Development of mobile applications, both cross platform and native.
- Effective communication skills; training, presentations, documentation and delegation.
- Practice and advocate the highest development standards.
- In-depth understanding of technologies across multiple domains.
- · Strong analytical thinking and problem solving skills.
- Life-long learner with strong interest in continuous professional development.

Tech stack

TypeScript	JavaScript (ES)	React / React Native	Redux Saga
Styled Components	SCSS / SASS / LESS	Progressive Web Apps	CSS Grid
NodeJS	ExpressJS	Docker Compose	MongoDB / Mongoose
Nginx	Linux	Web Components	webpack
Jest	React Testing Library	React Hooks	Ligthouse
CircleCl / Jenkins	Git	ESLint / Prettier / Stylelint	Xcode

Experience

Travelport Digital as senior front-end engineer

Dublin 01/2020 - present

- Worked on features for a mobile travel app and implemented upgrade path (React Native).
- Migrated client project from AngularJS to ReactJS with TypeScript.

Mobility Trader GmbH as senior front-end engineer

Berlin 01/2018 - 12/2019

- Created and maintained a marketplace and CRM for the HeyCar used car platform.
- · Mentored junior engineers, reviewed CVs and interviewed candidates

Freelance software engineer

Berlin 12/2014 - 01/2018

- Released two Meteor JS based packages for the open source community.
- Created a variety of web and mobile applications for numerous clients.

Things I Like GmbH as senior full-stack engineer

Berlin 06/2014 - 12/2014

- Built a website for the Monogi B2B platform for communication between designers and resellers.
- Created new tools to improve front end development workflow for the team.

Matt Finucane / CV 2 of 2

Axel Springer Ideas as senior front-end engineer

Berlin 10/2013 - 05/2014

- Created and maintained a TV guide web application for TunedIn, an Axel Springer startup.
- · Wrote unit and acceptance tests to ensure the product was stable throughout each sprint.

iQContent Ltd as senior full-stack engineer

Dublin 03/2013 - 09/2013

- Created a knowledge based information portal for a large telecoms organisation.
- Optimised registration flow and integrated this with other CRM tools such as Salesforce.

Maithú IT Solutions as technical lead

Dublin 01/2012 - 03/2013

- Drove the development of multiple mobile applications.
- Overhauled the Irish Times News app and integrated their existing web infrastructure.

Paddy Power PLC as senior full-stack engineer

Dublin 03/2010 - 01/2012

- Upgraded the in-house CMS to enable targeted content delivery for different user groups.
- Built a staff rostering and payroll system used by shop managers for all Paddy Power outlets.

ClearWeb as senior full-stack engineer

Dublin 07/2008 - 03/2010

- Created several bespoke content managed websites for clients using hand-coded html and php.
- Practiced excellent standards in web development to ensure organic SEO performance and accessibility.

Net a Porter as full-stack engineer

London 07/2007 - 07/2008

- Redeveloped the HTML and CSS during a complete overhaul of the company website.
- Created a WYSIWYG tool to author promotional emails and newsletter templates.

FindMyPast.com as full-stack engineer

London 09/2006 - 06/2007

- Upgraded site standards compliancy in XHTML and CSS.
- · Coordinated internal knowledge sharing through regular web standards training.

AOL Technologies as associate software engineer

Dublin 07/2005 - 06/2006

- Created a web app to monitor RSS feeds from news providers.
- Built an XSLT processor to populate XML feeds to databases.

Qualifications

BSc. in Computer Applications (Honours) // Dublin City University September 2001 - June 2005

- Modules included Java software development, Business process management, Computer Graphics, Database administration and the Software development life-cycle (waterfall).
- Alcatel CIT, France: created a logging system for GSM cell towers (INTRA work placement).
- Developed a mobile 2D game using J2ME (Final year project).

Interests

- Self taught with many experimental projects, which can be found on GitHub.
- Successfully participated in the '24 The Web' design challenge as lead developer.
- · Photography, technology, renewable energy, running and cycling.